<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guidance for Data Governance Decisions on LDaCA</title><link>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/</link><description>Recent content in Guidance for Data Governance Decisions on LDaCA</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>info@ldaca.edu.au (Language Data Commons of Australia)</managingEditor><webMaster>info@ldaca.edu.au (Language Data Commons of Australia)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:59:34 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LDaCA Onboarding Process</title><link>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/ldaca-onboarding-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:59:34 +1100</pubDate><author>info@ldaca.edu.au (Language Data Commons of Australia)</author><guid>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/ldaca-onboarding-process/</guid><description>LDaCA Onboarding Process Purpose Onboarding Process 1. Identifying relevant collections and initiating contact between LDaCA Data Stewards 2. Workplan 3. Determining appropriate governance and access conditions 4. Preparing data for cataloguing in LDaCA 5. Ongoing engagement Purpose This document outlines the standards and processes that support the onboarding of language collections to LDaCA. A successful onboarding will result in the collection being catalogued with LDaCA and made available in accordance with the specified access conditions.</description></item><item><title>Terms of Use</title><link>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/terms-of-use/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:51:23 +1100</pubDate><author>info@ldaca.edu.au (Language Data Commons of Australia)</author><guid>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/terms-of-use/</guid><description>LDaCA Terms of Use See the LDaCA Glossary for definitions of key terms and concepts.
I have read and agree to the Terms of Use.
or
By using this webpage, you agree to the Terms of Use.
Effective date: ____
Copyright for Data Collections is managed by the Data Steward via Data Access Licenses.
Data Access Licenses cannot be sub-licensed, transferred or assigned to others, unless otherwise permitted by the Data Steward.</description></item><item><title>Access Policy</title><link>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/access-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 12:49:58 +1100</pubDate><author>info@ldaca.edu.au (Language Data Commons of Australia)</author><guid>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/access-policy/</guid><description>Access Policy Purpose 1. Access Types and Licensing 2. Onboarding Data to LDaCA 3. Ongoing Data Management Strategy 4. Supporting Information Purpose This document outlines the LDaCA Access Policy, which is developed to accommodate the goal of making data appropriately accessible, in accordance with legal, moral and ethical considerations of data sharing, and tailored to meet the needs and requirements of different data collections.
Access conditions for data in LDaCA are determined by the Data Steward.</description></item><item><title>Determining Access Conditions</title><link>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/determining-access-conditions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 12:07:19 +1100</pubDate><author>info@ldaca.edu.au (Language Data Commons of Australia)</author><guid>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/determining-access-conditions/</guid><description>Determining Access Conditions Step 1: Consider access condition(s) for the entire collection Step 2: Organise relevant materials Step 3: Define the license terms Step 4: Determine authorisation level Options for access by application LDaCA recommends the following workflow to determine the access conditions to be outlined in the license. Examples of existing data access licenses can be found here.
Step 1: Consider access condition(s) for the entire collection Do the same access conditions apply to the entire collection?</description></item><item><title>Guidance for Data Governance Decisions</title><link>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>info@ldaca.edu.au (Language Data Commons of Australia)</author><guid>https://docs.ldaca.edu.au/using-ldaca/</guid><description>Purpose Data governance defines policies, roles, responsibilities and procedures for ongoing use and storage of data, as well as for access to data. Effective data governance maximises sustainability, while ensuring data integrity and protecting research participants. Long-term sustainability requires a data management plan.
This document provides guidance on some components of data governance that are key to a data management plan, including access conditions, licensing, persistent identifiers, and metadata. The principles below are those employed by LDaCA, but they are widely applicable and represent best practice for data governance, in accordance with the FAIR and CARE principles.</description></item></channel></rss>